Finding Aid for the Johanna Dordick Collection of Los Angeles Opera Theater Records PASC-M.0321
UCLA Library Special Collections
Johanna Dordick collection of Los Angeles Opera Theater records
1978-1987
UCLA Library Special Collections
Los Angeles Opera Theater
Dordick, Johanna
PASC-M.0321
6.8 linear feet (14 boxes, 1 flat box, 1 shoe box)
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email AskLSC@library.ucla.edu.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9966199443606533
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Johanna Dordick, 2010.
Historical Note
Johanna Dordrick (née Elizabeth Patricia Robinson) was born in Thomasville, Georgia in the midst of the 20th century. She discovered she loved singing at an early age and has pursued that path ever since. Her career has taken various forms, mostly based around performance, music, and singing with the Los Angeles Opera Theater (LAOT).
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of the personal donations of Johanna Dordick relating to the Los Angeles Opera Theater (originally named the Los Angeles Repertory Theater). Dordick founded Los Angeles Opera Theater in 1979 and served as the artistic director until her resignation in 1985. Los Angeles Opera Theater dissolved later that year.
Operas -- performances; Dordick, Johanna
- Business Papers, Series 1.
  - Financial, Subseries 1.
    - Financial Information, 1982-1986 (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents note
      Includes: budget outlines, public information and press clippings related to finances, ticket sales, contract outlines, administrative costs, accounts payable, balance sheets, donations received, projections, meeting notes, report to board of directors, fund planning analyses, personal financial notes.
    - Financial Information, 1985-1986 (Box 7)
      Includes: Wiltern Theater records, ticket sales, legal documents, projections, ticket solicitations, fundraising assignments, personal notes.
  - Administrative, Subseries 2.
    - Administrative Papers, 1978-1985 (Box 11)
      Includes: contacts, case statements, appointment books, meeting notes, campaign plans.
  - Legal, Subseries 3.
    - Legal Papers, 1985 (Box 12)
      Includes: contracts, board information, bylaws, legal notifications, attorney correspondence.
  - Publicity, Subseries 4.
    - Brochures and Solicitations, 1982-1986 (Box 10)
      Includes: brochures for opera seasons, solicitations for membership and ticket sales.
    - Periodicals with Notes, 1984-1987 (Box 9)
      Includes issues of: Opera/Musical Theatre Companies and Workshops in The United States and Canada, Opera News, Profile, Opera America, Los Angeles Times.
    - Press Clippings, 1981-1985 (Box 2)
      Includes: advertisements, newspapers, magazines, calendar listings, articles, LAOT history, reviews.
    - Publicity and Press, 1979-1985 (Box 8)
      Includes: advertisements, press releases, reviews, articles, collected quotes, magazines, solicitations.
- Productions, Series 2.
  - The Abduction from the Seraglio, 1981 (Box 3)
    Includes: invitations, promotional materials, programs.
  - Albert Herring, 1980 (Box 3)
    Includes: tickets, promotional material, programs, press clippings and reviews, photographs, slides, photographic negatives.
  - Anna Karenina, 1983 (Box 3)
    Includes: invitations, tickets, slides, photographs, reviews and press clippings.
  - Ariadne auf Naxos, 1981 (Box 3)
    Includes: tickets, photographs, slides, photographic negatives, reviews and press clippings.
  - La Boheme, 1981 (Box 3)
    Includes: tickets, reviews and press clippings, photographs, slides, photographic negatives.
  - Cosi Fan Tutte, 1982 (Box 4)
    Includes: tickets, reviews and press clippings, photographs, photographic negatives, slides.
  - Don Giovanni, 1985 (Box 4)
    Includes: photographs, invitations, promotional materials, reviews and press clippings, programs.
  - The Elixir Of Love, 1983 (Box 4)
    Includes: ticket, reviews and press clippings, photographs, slides, photographic negatives.
  - Die Fledermaus, 1984 (Box 4)
    Includes: tickets, photographs, slides, reviews and press clippings, promotional materials.
  - Gala Concert of Grand Opera, 1979 (Box 6)
    Includes: programs, tickets, promotional materials, reviews and press clippings, notes, correspondence, legal and administrative papers, headshots.
  - Lulu, 1984-1985 (Box 5)
    Includes: press clippings.
  - Madama Butterfly, 1984 (Box 5)
    Includes: reviews and press clippings, photographs, slides, promotional materials.
  - Opera Ball, 1983 (Box 5)
    Includes: tickets, invitations, programs.
  - Opera Studio, 1983 (Box 5)
    Includes: tickets, programs, reviews and press clippings.
  - Der Rosenkavalier, 1984 (Box 5)
    Includes: tickets, reviews and press clippings, letters, photographs, photographic negatives, slides.
  - Tosca, 1983 (Box 5)
    Includes: tickets, slides, photographs, photographic negatives.
  - La Traviata, 1982 (Box 5)
    Includes: tickets, photographs, photographic negatives, press clippings and reviews.
  - Unidentified Productions (Box 6)
    Includes: photographs, slides.
  - Unidentified Productions, undated (Box 15)
    Scope and Contents
    Three production design sketches.
- Audiovisual Material, Series 3.
  - Recordings (Box 14)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email AskLSC@library.ucla.edu.
    Includes cassette recordings of: Tosca, Madama Butterfly, La Boheme, unidentified productions Includes DVD recording of Der Rosenkavalier.
  - Audio cassettes, 1982-1984 (Box 16)
    CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIO MATERIALS: Audio materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email AskLSC@library.ucla.edu.
    Thirty-eight audio recordings of various performances.
- Personal Correspondence, Series 4.
  - Personal Correspondence and Photographs, 1980-1985 (Box 13)
    Includes: Johanna Dordick's personal letters, drafts, personal photographs and slides, book with personal dedications in it.